Guide to the Chi Phi, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Chi Phi, Yale University, records
1898-1960
RU 340
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.25
The records consist of correspondence, membership lists, a guest book, photograph, memorabilia, and a book of initiates.
Chi Phi (Fraternity). Omicron Chapter (Yale University)
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 40 (YRG 40), Records of Yale clubs, societies, and organizations.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
Chi Phi (also known as York Hall and the Omicron Trust Association) was established by Yale Sheffield Scientific School students in 1878. In 1897 they built a Venetian-palace-type house on the corner of Wall and College streets. The building (Stoeckel Hall), which Yale assumed ownership of in 1935, is now part of the Music School. The society disbanded in 1963.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, membership lists, a guest book, photograph, memorabilia, and a book of initiates.
College students -- Societies, etc.; Greek letter societies; Chi Phi Fraternity. Omicron Chapter (Yale University. Sheffield Scientific School); Yale University -- Societies, etc.; Yale University -- Students
- Records, 1952-1960; Accession 19ND-A-480
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Membership lists, 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Guest book for York Hall, 1952-1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Emblem of R. Gilfillan (Box 1, Folder 5)
    General
    See: YRG 40 folio
  - Book of initiates (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Catalogue of books: index file (Box 3, Folder 7)
    See also: Yale Clubs folio #1
- Design for Chi Phi symbol, 1898; Accession 1994-A-150
  - Design for Chi Phi symbol, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Photographs of Chi Phi members, circa 1928; Accession 1996-A-063
  - Photograph of Chi Phi members, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Photograph of Chi Phi members at York Hall, Undated (Box 1)